

MATIAS GIMENEZ

Frontend Developer



Profile

I'm a web designer oriented frontend. Da Vinci School graduate in 2010, I have worked in various high traffic websites as MercadoLibre, DeAutos, in which I could gain experience in UI / UX development considering the performance as much as the code semantics.

Since 2010 I work as a freelance in developing web sites and applications meeting the deadlines and ensuring proper operation.

I also work as employees in Eulas where I am part of a team of 10 people developing e-commerce webapp for different brands.

Passionate about technology, I'm continually increasing my knowledge to keep me updated.

Skills

| Semantic HTML 5 | UX / UI Development | PHP / Code Igniter |
|-------------------------|---------------------|--------------------|
| CSS 3 / COMPASS | DOM / AJAX / JSON | My Sql |
| Vanilla Javascript | Grunt | Photoshop |
| jQuery / jQuery UI | WPO | Illustrator |
| Responsive Web Design | APIs | Fireworks |
| Progressive Enhancement | GIT | Scrum |

Experience

Eulas

05/2015-Actual

Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3 / COMPASS
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- Handlebars Frontend Improvements
- Google Apis
- Grunt
- Responsive Web Design
- JBoss
- GIT

DeAutos

01/2015-05/2015

Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- JS Frameworks
- Frontend Improvements
- WPO (Web Performance Optimization)
- Grunt / Gulp
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT

Mercadolibre

08/2012-01/2015

Frontend Developer UI/UX

- Semantic HTML5
- CSS3
- Vanilla JavaScript / jQuery
- Chico UI (JS Framework)
- Components & Libraries Development • Progressive Enhancement
- Responsive Web Design
- GIT
- Grails / Groovy
- Frontend Meetups

8a Marketing Comunicacion y Diseño

06/2011-08/2012

- Web Implementer Semantic HTML
- CSS
- jQuery / jQuery UI
- PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql
- Newsletters

Joptiwebs 2010-Current

Freelance Development

- Corporative Sites, Institutional, Drupal Development.
- Semantic HTML
- CSS / CSS3 / SASS • JS / jQuery / jQuery UI
- PHP, CodeIgniter, My Sql

03/2008-08/2010

Education

Escuela Multimedial Da Vinci

Designer & Manager Web sites oriented programming

- Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash. • HTML - XHTML / CSS 2.1
- Javascript / Jquery
- PHP5 MVC / Doctrine Framework / Zend Framework
- MySQL
- WAMP

Universidad Tecnologica Nacional

03/2004-08/2005

1997-2002

Technician in Programming

- Approved subjects: 11/20. • Structure of computer systems, Features OS
- Computer Security (Antivirus, Firewall, Spy, Spam, etc.)
- Maintain an optimal PC.
- Structure of a PC, Micropocesadores, Memories, Peripherals. • C & C++

Technical School Reconquista de BsAs. (High School)

Computer technician

- C & C++
- Visual Basic
- Fox Pro

Matias Gimenez —matias.gimenez@gmail.com —(+54) - 15 3 282 9461